Finding Aid for the Stafford Leak Warren Papers LSC.0987
UCLA Library Special Collections
- III. Operation Crossroads Papers.
  - Assorted Reports and Dispatches., August-October 1946.; 23 items:
    - 1. Report, Review of Radiological Safety Measures., June 30, 1946.; (5pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 2. Copy report, review of Radiological Safety Measures., undated; (5pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 3. Graph, predicted decay of active deposits., undated. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 4. Copy dispatch, Kelly, USEO to Dist. Eng., USEO., August 8, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 5. Copy dispatch, Kelly, USEO to Washington Liaison Office., August 8, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 6. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (Captain Bednarczyk)., August 22, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 7. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (pass to Captain Bednarczyk)., September 2, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 8. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to CWSF (Captain Bednarczyk)., September 26, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 9. Copy dispatch, Captain S.P. Bednarczyk to Colonel Nichols., undated (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 10. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to Com. General Manhattan Project., October 29, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 11. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to NDS Oakland (Major Bundage)., October 4, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 12. Rough chart, Bikini radiation count., August 20, 1946.; (5pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 13. Copy chart, Bikini radiation count., August 20-October 15, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 14. Copy message form, Washington H.Q. to Area Engineer USEO Berkeley., October 17, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 15. Copy dispatch, Roper, Washington H.Q. to D. Min., October 23, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 16. Copy dispatch, from Derry, USEO., undated (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 17. Copy dispatch, Roper, Washington H.Q. to AE, USEO, Berkeley., October 25, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 18. Copy dispatch, Derry, Washington H.Q. to AE, USEO, Berkeley., October 25, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 19. Memo with sketches, William H.B. Howard, Maj. CWS Radiological Monitor to SLW., undated; (3pp. total). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 20. Memo [report], DSM Monitors, Baker Test, William H.B. Howard, Maj. CWS to SLW., undated; (6pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 21. Copy graph, Alpha-ray hazards, Baker Test., undated (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 22. Copy report, Radiological Monitoring of Ships Returning from Operation Crossroads., undated; (4pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 23. Copy list, badge readings, Test Able., undated; (29pp.). (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Reports and Samples., August 1946.; 12 items:
    - 1. Graph, Beta counts per minute., July 6, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 2. Memo, pill counting lab to SLW., August 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 3. Rough memo, pill counting lab to SLW., August 9, 1946. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 4. Rough dispatch, boat propeller radioactivity., undated (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 5. Rough notes., undated (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 6. Report, Preliminary Estimates of Gamma Dose on Target Ships, Test Baker., undated; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 7. Copy enclosures, Downwind Destroyer Reports., undated; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 8. Copy diagram, radiation intensity above water, Baker Day., undated (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 9. Dispatch, Commander Service Force, United States Pacific Fleet., undated; (2pp.). (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 10. Envelope with dust samples from U.S.S. Henrico., undated (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 11. Report with samples, Rust and Debris Readings., August-November 1946. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 12. Original folder containing samples., undated (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Assorted Letters, Reports and Dispatches., September-October 1946.; 14 items:
    - 1. Copy naval dispatch, General Nichols and SLW to Com. West. Sea Fron. (pass to Captain Bednarczyk)., September 22, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 2. Copy letter [list], travel expenses, L.G. Hawkins to S.P. Bednarczyk., September 30, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 3. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to Captain Bednarczyk., October 4, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 4. Copy naval dispatch, Radiological Safety Advisor to Captain Bednarczyk., October 5, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 5. Copy cover letter, for SFNS Health Physics Report, W.H. Ray to Captain W.E. Walsh., October 7, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 6. Copy report, SFNS Health Physics Report for Week Ending October 6, 1946, by W.H. Ray. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 7. Copy letter, Stanley P. Bednarczyk to P.M. Douglas., October 11, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 8. Copy memo, Stanley L. Stewart, Area Engineer, to A.E. Dyhre., October 18, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 9. Copy letter [Stanley L. Stewart, A.E.] to Dr. N.E. Bradbury, Att: A.E. Dyhre., October 18, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 10. Memo, John F. Bonner to Dr. Fred Bryan., October 23, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 11. Copy memo, John F. Bonner to Dr. Fred Bryan., October 23, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 12. Letter, George Vaux, Commander, USNR, to SLW., October 25, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 13. Copy letter [report], Measurements on Neoprene Washers, Fred A. Bryan, Assistant to Medical Advisor, Manhattan District, to Dr. Herbert Scoville., October 29, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 14. Rough memo, neoprene washers, to SLW., undated (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Letters, Reports and Memos., November 1946.; 7 items:
    - 1. Signed copy cover letter, report of samples shipped by Radiological Safety, Wright Langham to Dr. Herbert Scoville., November 5, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 2. Copy report, Analysis of Samples Sent by Radiological Safety Section., November 15, 1946.; (8pp.). (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 3. Copy letter, Herbert Scoville, Jr. to Dr. Lauren Donaldson., November 6, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 4. Copy letter, Herbert Scoville, Jr. to Dr. Milton Burton., November 8, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 5. Memo, Lee W. Fritter, Captain to Chief of Radiological Safety Section., November 20, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 6. Copy memo [report], Comments on Results of the Investigations on the U.S.S. Rockbridge, Dr. Herbert Scoville, Jr. to Captain G.M. Lyon., November 21, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 7. Copy letter, Herbert Scoville, Jr. to Dr. Kenneth Scott., November 26, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Letters and Memos., December 1946.; 27 items:
    - 1. Copy form note, John W. Martyn to General Groves., December 14, 1945. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 2. Memo routing slip, from Bundage., [December 18, no year].; [Cover note]. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 3. Letter, Thomas D. Rice, Massachusetts Fisheries Association, Incorporated to Hon. Robert P. Patterson., December 12, 1945. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 4. Copy letter, SLW to Thomas D. Rice., December 28, 1945.; (2 duplicates). (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 5. Copy letter, Herbert Scoville, Jr. to Dr. Wright Langham., December 3, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 6. Copy telegram, B.H. Caldwell to SLW., undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 7. Cover letter for William G. Myers' report, William G. Myers to SLW., December 9, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 8. Copy report, Observations of Tests Able and Baker, by William G. Myers, M.D., August 28, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 9. Copy memo, Dr. Fred A. Bryan to Dr. Andrew H. Dowdy., December 10, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 10. Copy memo, Dr. Fred A. Bryan to Dr. William Bale., December 10, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 11. Copy memo, Dr. Fred A. Bryan to J. Russell Hayes., December 10, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 12. Copy memo, Dr. Fred A. Bryan to Dr. John Bonner., December 10, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 13. Copy memo, Dr. Fred A. Bryan to Dr. Curt Stern., December 10, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 14. Copy memo, Dr. Fred A. Bryan to Dr. Donald Charles., December 10, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 15. Copy memo, Dr. Fred A. Bryan to Dr. George Suter., December 10, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 16. Copy memo, Dr. Fred A. Bryan to Captain William Valentine., December 10, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 17. Copy memo, Clifford A. Swanson, Rear Admiral to the Surgeon General., December 11, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 18. Copy letter, Herbert Scoville, Jr. to Dr. John E. Rose., December 11, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 19. Copy schedule., December 16-17, 1946, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 20. Memo routing slip, to Captain Brundage and General Groves., undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 21. Memo, Walter W. Stagg, Maj. Corps of Engineers to Chief of Medical Section, Manhattan District, Att: Stanley Bednarczyk., November 18, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 22. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to Lieutenant Colonel Stewart., December 9, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 23. Copy letter, Herbert Scoville, Jr., to Dr. Gerhard Dessauer., December 19, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 24. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to Mr. Walter W. Stagg., December 23, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 25. Copy memo, Dr. Andrew H. Dowdy to Drs. Bale, Suter, Valentine, Charles, Stern and Bonner., November 29, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 26. Memo, Andrew H. Dowdy to Dr. Fred Bryan., November 29, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 27. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. William G. Myers., December 31, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Letters, Reports and Memos., August 1946-July 1950.; (54 items)
    Note: for items 1-7 see also typed reports, Box 76, Folder 3, Items 55-64.
    - 1. Rough report, Pu on Decks, by Newell. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 2. Rough report, Pu Hazard, Welding and Cutting, by Newell. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 3. Rough report, Pu Hazards Evaporators, by Newell., undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 4. Rough report, Pu Hazards Pipes, by Newell., undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 5. Rough report, Pu Hazards Summary, by Newell., undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 6. Rough report, Pu Hazards Suggested Tolerance Limits, by Newell., undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 7. Graph, Gamma tolerance limits based on inferred plutonium contamination, by Newell., undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 8. Rough memo [report], Gamma-Alpha Equivalence for Flat Surfaces, R.R. Coveyou., August 26, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 9. Copy memo [report], Gamma-Alpha Equivalence for Flat Surfaces, R.R. Coveyou to SLW., August 26, 1946.; (2 duplicates). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 10-16. Assorted graphs, radiation levels., [August 1946].; (7 items). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 17-19. Assorted nautical charts with notes, Bikini Atoll, printed., March 1946.; (3 items). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 20. Copy memo, SLW to Commanding General, H.Q., 1st Army., undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 21. Copy dispatch, CJTF-One to U.S.S. Haven., October 23 [undated]. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 22. Copy memo, Thomas H. Prescott, Captain, Infantry to Commanding Officer, H.Q., JTF-One., October 24, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 23. Copy messageform, Calexico Engineering Works to Project Director, Los Alamos, New Mexico., December 24, 1946. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 24. Memo [report] with tables, Residual Radioactivity on Crossroads Target Vessels, Technical Analysis Section (Herbert Scoville, Jr.) to SLW., January 4, 1947.; (6pp. total). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 25. Letter, W.S. Parsons to SLW., January 3, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 26. Copy letter, W.S. Parsons to SLW., January 3, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 27. Copy memo [report], Hazards from Residual Radioactivity on the Crossroads Target Vessels, SLW to Admiral W.S. Parsons., January 6, 1947.; (4pp.). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 28. Copy letter, SLW to Admiral W.S. Parsons., January 8, 1947.; (2 duplicates). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 29. Letter, W.S. Parsons to SLW., January 10, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 30. Copy letter, W.S. Parsons to SLW., January 10, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 31. Copy report, Effective Distance, Nuclear Radiation., January 12, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 32. Copy memo, Robert J. Buettner to Major B.M. Brundage., January 16, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 33. Copy letter, SLW to Admiral W.S. Parsons., January 18, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 34. Copy memo [report], Wartime Radiation Tolerances, SLW to Admiral W.S. Parsons., January 18, 1947.; (2 duplicates, 3pp. each). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 35. Memo, W.N. Sullivan, Jr., Surgeon Office, H.Q., SAC to SLW., January 24, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 36. Copy letter, SLW to Rear Admiral Parsons., January 30, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 37. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to Carroll Wilson, General Manager, Atomic Energy Commission., January 30, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 38. Letter, W.S. Parsons to SLW., February 21, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 39. Copy memo, H. Scoville, Jr. to Technical Director., February 24, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 40. Memo, Adjutant General to SLW., March 31, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 41. Copy memo, Robert J. Buettner to Lieutenant Colonel Stanley L. Stewart., April 25, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 42. Copy memo [report], Ensign Coffin, George M. Lyon to Admiral Parsons., May 5, 1947.; (7pp.). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 43. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to Stanley L. Stewart, Area Manager, Atomic Energy Commission., July 21, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 44. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to John Macy, Atomic Energy Commission., February 24, 1948. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 45. Letter, John Z. Bowers, M.D. to SLW., March 4, 1948. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 46. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Herbert Scoville., March 11, 1948. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 47. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to John Macy, Atomic Energy Commission., March 15, 1948. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 48. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to Colonel James P. Cooney, H.Q., JTF-Seven., March 15, 1948. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 49. Copy letter, Robrt J. Buettner to Dr. Norris E. Bradbury, Atomic Energy Commission., March 15, 1948. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 50. Letter, Herbert Scoville, Jr. to SLW., March 16 [undated].; (2pp.). (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 51. Letter, Kenneth G. Scott to SLW., July 14, 1950. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 52. Copy graph, Bikini decay curves, K.G. Scott and K. Larson., [July 14, 1950]. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 53. Copy list, suggested subjects for comments, Bikini Tests., undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 54. Photo, bomb damage., undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Assorted material and courier receipts, Operation Crossroads., March 15-May 9, 1949.; 66 items. (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Publications With Letter., April 1947-April 1967.; 3 items:
    - 1. Copy letter, SLW to Captain George Lyon., April 7, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - 2. Publication, reprinted from The Scientific Monthly, vol.62 no.2, February 1951, Bikini Report, by Neal O. Hines. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - 3. Publication, reprinted from Science Journal, ref. no.67/190, April 1967, Bikini Nine Years Later. (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Reports With Letter., November 1946-February 1947.; 8 items:
    - 1. Copy published report, from The Military Engineer, Instruments of Operation Crossroads, by Jack DeMent, research chemist., undated; (5 duplicates, 6pp. each). (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 2. Negative copy published report, from The Military Engineer, Instruments of Operation Crossroads, by Jack DeMent, research chemist., undated; (6pp.). (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 3. Copy report with folder, Radiological Safety School Bureau of Medicine and Surgery, Navy Department,, Arthur B. Cutts, Officer-in-Charge., November 25-December 9, 1946, December 20, 1946.; (44pp. including folder). (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 4. Report with folder, Operation Crossroads, Reports to Radiological Safety Instrument Division,, D.L. Collins, Chief, Radiological Safety Instrumental Division., May 29-August 7, 1946, undated.; (58pp. total). (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 5. Cover letter, for telemetering reports, D.L. Collins to SLW., February 3, 1947. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 6. Report with folder, Operation Crossroads, Radiation Measurements by Radio Telemeters, Final Report, Instrument Division, Radiological Safety Section, JTF-One., February 1, 1947.; (25pp. including folder). (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 7. Copy report with folder, Operation Crossroads, Radiation Measurements by Radio Telemeters, Final Report, Instrument Division, Radiological Safety Section, JTF-One., February 1, 1947.; (3 duplicates, 25pp. each including folder). (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 8. Copy report with folder, Crossroads Hand book, by J.O. Hirschfelder and J.L. Magee., undated; (101 p. including folder). (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Report With Note., October 1946.; 2 items:
    - 1. Note, deleted addenda due to classification restrictions., undated (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - 2. Copy report, The Radiological Safety School, JTF-One, Navy Department,, by D.L. Kauffman, Officer-in-Charge., September 9-October 9, 1946, October 14, 1946.; (68pp.). (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Lecture Notes., May-June 1946.; 35 items:
    - 1. Copy cover letter, John H. Lawrence, M.D. to SLW., March 26, 1946. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 2. Copy list, lecture series on medical physics., March 26, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 3. Lecture notes: Organization and Life aboard a Navy Ship, Lieut. Commander A.J. Ryan; Preservation of Health and Comfort at Sea and in the Tropics, Captain Parsons; Normal Security Practices Applying to this Ship, Lieut. Commander A.E. Aman; JTF-One Staff Organization, Captain George Lyon; General Aspects of Safety during Operations, Captain George Lyon., May 30, 1946.; (12pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 4. Copy lecture notes: Organization and Life aboard a Navy Ship, Lieutenant Commander A.J. Ryan; Preservation of Health and Comfort at Sea and in the Tropics, Captain Parsons; Normal Security Practices Applying to this Ship, Lieut. Commander A.E. Aman; JTF-One Staff Organization, Captain George Lyon; General Aspects of Safety during Operations, Captain George Lyon., May 30, 1946.; (12pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 5. Copy lecture notes: Organization and Life aboard a Navy Ship, Lieut. Commander A.J. Ryan; Preservation of Health and Comfort at Sea and in the Tropics, Captain Parsons; Normal Security Practices Applying to this Ship, Lieutenant Commander A.E. Aman; JTF-One Staff Organization, Captain George Lyon; General Aspects of Safety during Operations, Captain George Lyon., undated; (2 duplicates, 8pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 6. Lecture notes: Radiological Safety Section (General) Mission and Orgaization, SLW; Radiological Safety Section (General) Relation to other Sections, SLW; Damage Control Safety Section Mission and Organization, Captain O. Schneider; Oceanographic Section, Organization and Function, Dr. M.P. O'Brien and Lieutenant Commander Lyman; Air Operations - Crossroads, Lieutenant Colonel J.M. Talbot and Ensign H. Walton., May 31, 1946.; (15pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 7. Copy lecture notes: Radiological Safety Section (General) Mission and Organization, SLW; Radiological Safety Section (General) Relation to other Sections, SLW; Damage Control Safety Section Mission and Organization, Captain O. Schneider; Oceanographic Section, Organization and Function, Dr. M.P. O'Brien and Lieutenant Commander Lyman; Air Operations - Crossroads, Lieutenant Colonel J.M. Talbot and Ensign H. Walton., May 31, 1946.; (15pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 8. Copy lecture notes, Air Operations, Lieutenant Colonel J.M. Talbot and Ensign H. Walton., undated; (2pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 9. Copy lecture notes, Air Operations, Lieutenant Colonel J.M. Talbot and Ensign H. Walton., undated; (2 duplicates, 2pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 10. Copy lecture notes, Oceanographic Section, Dean M.P. O'Brien and Lieutenant Commander Lyman., undated; (2 duplicates, 7pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 11. Lecture notes, Damage Control Safety Section, Captain O. Schneider., undated; (3pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 12. Copy lecture notes, Damage Control Safety Section, Captain O. Schneider., undated; (2 duplicates, 2pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 13. Lecture notes, Damage Control Safety Section, Captain O. Schneider., undated; (2pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 14. Copy lecture notes, Damage Control Safety Section, Captain O. Schneider., undated; (2 duplicates). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 15. Lecture notes, Geiger-Muller Counters, Henry Faul., undated; (3pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 16. Copy lecture notes, Geiger-Muller Counters, Henry Faul., undated; (2 duplicates, 2pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 17. Lecture notes: Quartz Fiber Instruments, Dr. O.A. Landsverk; Portable Counting Instruments, Henry Faul; Ion Chambers, Gamma Types, C.D. Gould; Ion Chambers, Alpha and Beta Types, M. Shandor., June 1, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 18. Copy lecture notes, Quartz Fiber Instruments, Dr. O.A. Landsverk., undated; (2pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 19. Lecture notes, Ion Chambers, Alpha and Beta Types, M. Shandor., June 1, 1946.; (5pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 20. Copy lecture notes, Ion Chambers, Alpha and Beta Types, M. Shandor., (2 duplicates, 2pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 21. Lecture notes: Instruments: Data and Calibration, D.L. Collins; Practical Measurements, D.L. Collins and assistants; Principles of Damage Control, Captain O. Schneider., June 2, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 22. Copy lecture notes, Instruments: Data Calibrations, D.L. Collins., undated; (2 duplicates). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 23. Lecture notes: Atomic Structure, Dr. G. Dessauer; Nuclear Structure, Dr. G. Dessauer., June 3, 1946.; (7pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 24. Lecture notes: Orientation, SLW; Instrumentation, Senior Monitors; Geiger Counters, Frank E. Dudley., June 6, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 25. Lecture notes: Communications, Radiological Safety Section Network, Commander D.L. Kauffman; Instrumentation, Senior Monitors; Atomic Energies: Their Peacetime Application, Dr. R.E. Lapp., June 7, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 26. Copy calculations with notes, neutrons., undated; (2pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 27. Copy schedule, basic intensive course in radiological safety for monitors., undated; (2pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 28. Lecture notes, Photometry, Dr. G. Dessauer; Instrumentation, Senior Monitors., June 8, 1946.; (7pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 29. Copy lecture notes, Photometry, Dr. Gerhard Dessauer., undated; (3pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 30. Lecture notes: The Tolerance Dose, Dr. R. Newell, Dr. E. Pendergrass, and Mr. Marinelli; Expectant Radiation Exposures During the Bikini Operation, SLW; Instrumentation, Senior Monitors., June 11, 1946.; (9pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 31. Rough lecture notes, The Tolerance Dose, R.R. Newell., June 11, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 32. Copy lecture notes, The Tolerance Dose, Dr. R. Newell, Dr. E.P. Pendergrass and L.D. Marinelli., undated; (4pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 33. Lecture notes: Electromagnetic Radiation from the Atom Bomb, Dr. Billings; Instrumentation, Senior Monitors., June 12, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 34. Lecture notes: Electromagnetic Radiation from the Atom Bomb, Dr. Billings; Instrumentation, Senior Monitors., June 12, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 35. Copy lecture notes, Electromagnetic Radiation from the Atomic Bomb, Dr. B. Billings., undated; (2 duplicates, 2pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Lecture Notes., undated; 9 items:
    - 1. Copy lecture notes, One Million Volt X-Ray Machine, Dr. H. Mormagen., undated; (2 duplicates, 4pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - 2. Copy lecture, notes, Cosmic Rays, Dr. R.E. Lapp., undated; (2 duplicates, 5pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - 3. Copy lecture notes, Electromagnetic Separation at Oak Ridge, Lieutenant Colonel W.E. Kelly., undated; (2 duplicates, 5pp. each). (Box 78, Folder 2)